<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>4.17面试准备</title>
    <link href="/2025/04/17/4-17%E9%9D%A2%E8%AF%95%E5%87%86%E5%A4%87/"/>
    <url>/2025/04/17/4-17%E9%9D%A2%E8%AF%95%E5%87%86%E5%A4%87/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="4-17面试的提前准备"><a href="#4-17面试的提前准备" class="headerlink" title="4.17面试的提前准备"></a>4.17面试的提前准备</h1><p>Good morning, sir. My name is  . I graduated from   Science and Technology College in 2024, majoring in Computer Science. , I’m really interested in the POS Technical Support Analyst position. My main strength is really good problem-solving.             I think about systems in pieces to see how they connect which means modular thinking , and I’m good at figuring out exactly what’s wrong in it.                                                                       During my internship, I usually solved problems in less than two hours, especially by looking at logs, like Java logs  and the  browser Developer tools。</p><p>I have a good working knowledge of Java and SQL (I’ve used both MySQL and Oracle), and that’s exactly what you’re looking for.     And I’m comfortable working in Linux – also a key requirement.</p><p>Even though I haven’t worked with POS systems          specifically before, I’m organized, good at analyzing things, and have a strong background in fixing problems, looking at logs, databases, and Linux. So, I’m confident I can learn quickly and       help       keep your systems stable and reliable.</p><p>I’m excited to use my technical skills to help your team. Thanks!”</p><h2 id="2-面试题预先猜想参考"><a href="#2-面试题预先猜想参考" class="headerlink" title="2.面试题预先猜想参考"></a><strong>2.面试题预先猜想参考</strong></h2><p>常用的Linux命令<br>ls cd rm cp mv find<br>top htop ps kill free df（看磁盘空间）</p><p>chmod chown sudo </p><p>ping netstat ss ifconfig</p><p>cat tail -f less -f grep </p><p>SQL</p><p>表连接其实就是先把两表求出笛卡尔积，然后再加上条件过滤</p><p>内连接 返回 两表同时存在的数据</p><p>左连接 返回 左表全部数据和右表与条件匹配的数据</p><p>右连接 返回 右表全部数据和左表与条件匹配的数据</p><p>A POS terminal has functions like transaction processing, product management and receipt printing.</p><ul><li><p><strong>交易处理</strong>：顾客购买眼镜时，可使用信用卡、借记卡或移动支付等方式付款，POS 系统读取支付信息后，将交易数据传至银行或支付处理机构进行验证与授权，快速完成支付流程。</p></li><li><p><strong>Transaction Processing</strong>: When customers buy glasses, they can pay with a credit card, debit card, or mobile payment. The POS system reads the payment info and sends the transaction data to the bank or payment processor to get it checked and approved, and then finishes the payment really fast.</p></li></ul><p>比如，顾客用信用卡支付一副价值 500 元的眼镜，POS 机读取卡片信息，经银行验证授权后，从顾客账户扣除相应金额，商家则收到款项。</p><p>For example, if a customer pays 500 yuan for a pair of glasses with a credit card, the POS machine reads the card info. After the bank checks and approves it, the money is taken out of the customer’s account, and the store gets paid.</p><ul><li><p><strong>商品管理</strong>：眼镜店的 POS 系统与库存管理系统集成。当销售眼镜时，系统自动更新库存信息，减少相应款式眼镜的库存数量，并记录销售数据，如销售时间、款式、价格等。</p></li><li><p><strong>Merchandise（product） Management</strong>: The POS system in the glasses store is linked to the inventory system. When we sell glasses, the system updates the stock info automatically. It cuts down the number of those glasses in stock and writes down sales details, like when we sold them, what style they are, and how much they cost.</p></li></ul><p>这有助于商家了解哪些款式受欢迎，以便及时补货或调整采购策略。</p><ul><li><p><strong>打印票据</strong>：交易完成后，POS 系统打印销售小票给顾客，作为购买凭证。</p></li><li><p><strong>Receipt Printing</strong>: After the deal is done, the POS system prints a receipt for the customer. It’s the proof of purchase.</p></li></ul><p>小票上包含交易时间、购买的眼镜款式及价格、支付方式等详细信息。</p><p>The receipt has details like when the sale happened, what glasses were bought, how much they cost, and how the customer paid.</p><p>若顾客需要退换货或维修，小票可作为重要依据。</p><p>If the customer wants to return, exchange, or get the glasses fixed, the receipt is really important.</p><p>This helps the store owners know which styles are hot, so they can restock quickly or change their buying plans.</p><p>比如，某款时尚镜框销量大增，商家通过 POS 系统的销售数据得知后，可及时联系供应商补货。</p><p>For example, if a trendy frame sells a lot, once the store owner sees the sales data on the POS system, they can call the supplier right away to restock.</p><ol><li><p><strong>详细询问</strong>：向报告人了解问题出现的具体情况，包括出现问题的时间、地点、操作步骤、问题表现（如交易失败、无法读卡、打印错误等）以及涉及的具体 POS 机编号或位置。</p></li><li><p><strong>Ask in Detail</strong>：Ask the person who reported the problem about the specific situation. Find out when and where the problem happened, what steps they took, how the problem showed up (like transaction failure, can’t read the card, wrong printing, etc.), and the specific POS machine number or location involved.</p></li><li><p><strong>重启设备</strong>：尝试重启 POS 机，看是否能解决问题。有时候，一些临时的软件故障可以通过重启来修复。</p></li><li><p><strong>Restart the Device</strong>：Try reboot  the POS machine to see if it fixes the problem. Sometimes, a temporary software glitch can be fixed by reboot.</p></li><li><p><strong>查看日志</strong>：进入 POS 机的系统日志或交易记录界面，查看是否有相关的错误代码或异常记录。这些日志可以提供关于问题发生时的详细信息，帮助定位问题所在。</p></li><li><p><strong>Check Logs</strong>：Go into the system logs or transaction record page of the POS machine. Look for any relevant error codes or unusual records. These logs can give detailed info about when the problem happened and help find where the problem is.</p></li></ol><p>Transaction Testing</p><ol><li><p><strong>模拟交易</strong>：使用测试卡片或虚拟交易功能，在 POS 机上进行各种类型的交易测试，如刷卡、插卡、挥卡、移动支付等，观察是否能正常完成交易</p></li><li><p><strong>Simulate Transactions</strong>：Use test cards or the virtual transaction function to do different types of transaction tests on the POS machine, to see the transaction is completely works</p></li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>近期各大模型主观使用体验总结</title>
    <link href="/2025/03/28/%E8%BF%91%E6%9C%9F%E5%90%84%E5%A4%A7%E6%A8%A1%E5%9E%8B%E4%B8%BB%E8%A7%82%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8%E4%BD%93%E9%AA%8C/"/>
    <url>/2025/03/28/%E8%BF%91%E6%9C%9F%E5%90%84%E5%A4%A7%E6%A8%A1%E5%9E%8B%E4%B8%BB%E8%A7%82%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8%E4%BD%93%E9%AA%8C/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="近期各大模型主观使用体验总结"><a href="#近期各大模型主观使用体验总结" class="headerlink" title="近期各大模型主观使用体验总结"></a><strong>近期各大模型主观使用体验总结</strong></h1><table><thead><tr><th>平台</th><th>AI模型的强项与特点</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><a href="https://chatgpt.com/">ChatGPT</a></td><td>- 支持多国语言，翻译能力相对不错<br>- 对网络环境要求较高<br>- 登陆后更“聪明”</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://chat.deepseek.com/">DeepSeek</a></td><td>- 深度思考，提供更学术、更准确的解决方案<br>- 不适合短文和短语翻译<br>- 思考时间较长</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://www.doubao.com/chat/">豆包</a></td><td>- 反应快，翻译与图片识别能力相对不错<br>- 网络环境不好、翻译专业度不高时也能胜任大部分任务<br>- 提供口语练习能力（仅支持中英）</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://gemini.google.com/app?hl=zh">Gemini</a></td><td>- 由谷歌提供的大模型，免费且容量大<br>- 能够处理非常长的文本对话<br>- 多能力：p图、识别图片&#x2F;视频内容和文字<br>- 支持多种外语识别与翻译，专业性相对不错</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://claude.ai/">Claude</a></td><td>- 在编程任务方面很强<br>- 准确度高<br>- 价格较贵</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://grok.com/">Grok3</a></td><td>- 适合搜集信息，可全英文搜索互联网<br>- 能避免中文语料干扰<br>- 提供语言对话能力，表现相对不错</td></tr><tr><td><a href="https://chat.qwen.ai/">千问</a></td><td>- 日语支持能力较好<br>- 能解答多种语言问题</td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
